STEPHEN PUTHENPURACKAL

CONTACT

Address: Mesquite, TX 75149

Phone: 469-735-7590

Email:

puthenpurackalstephen@gmail.com

WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

- GitHub.com/datfoosteve
- · LinkedIn.com/puthenpurackalstephen

SKILLS

- C++
- JavaScript
- JAVA
- Python
- CSS
- HTML
- TypeScript
- SQL
- Redux/Apollo
- NodeJs
- MERN Stack
- REACT
- PHP
- · Graphic and User Interface Design
- WordPress

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 2 years of related experience. Complex problem-solver with analytical, and driven mindset. Dedicated to delivering high-quality customer service, building customer relations.

WORK HISTORY

Technology Manager, 05/2023 to Current **ETHOS Brand** - Dallas, TX

- Developed suggestions for technical process improvements to optimize resources.
- Managed implementation of new technological improvements resulting in increased efficiency.
- WordPress/ Elementor/ PHP
- Analyzed company processes to determine outsourcing feasibility.

Web Developer, 11/2022 to 05/2023 Momenta Tech - Houston, TX

- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery languages.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX and JSON coding.
- Provided front-end website development using WordPress and other editing software.
- Oversaw back-end development using PHP to maintain website integrity, security and efficiency.

Pharmacy Technician, 08/2014 to 08/2016 **CVS Pharmacy** - Wichita Falls, TX

- Answered incoming phone calls and addressed questions from customers and healthcare providers.
- Calculated dosage, filled prescriptions and prepared prescription labels with absolute accuracy.
- Counted and labeled prescriptions with correct item and quantity.
- Stocked, labeled and inventoried medication to keep accurate records.

EDUCATION

Coding Bootcamp, Full Stack Web: Web Development, 02/2022 **Southern Methodist University** - Dallas, TX

CERTIFICATIONS

Full Stack Web Developer